

codes.mariam@gmail.com



www.mariam.codes



github.com/mavima



linkedin.com/in/maria-vihla-manninen

MARIA MANNINEN

WEB DEVELOPER

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Originally a journalist, I have also worked in administration in international environment. A couple of years ago I decided to learn to code and found my new career. At the moment I am working on my own application and other websites, while always keeping on learning.

TOP SKILLS

- Ruby & Ruby on Rails
- HTML / CSS
- JavaScript & React
- jQuery
- SQL
- PHP
- WordPress
- Photoshop
- Project management

PERSONAL WEB PROJECTS

- → www.recipeper.com Recipeper is a bilingual RoR application for storing recipes and links. Leave a comment, write a personal note or send the recipe to your email address.
- → www.famtravel.eu Famtravel is a community travelling families sharing tips - meant to make it easier to visit other cities also with children.

EXPERIENCE

Since September 2019:

Freelance web developer

- Creating websites for clients using Wordpress as CMS.
- Developing applications for personal projects using Ruby on Rails and React.

9/2015 - 4/2019: Nordea Investment Funds S.A.

Business Support Officer

- Event organization and assistance of the management
- Expense follow-up and reporting.

5/2013 - 8/2015: Embassy of Finland in Luxembourg

Assistant of the ambassador

11/2012 - 5/2013 : Rovi Corporation S.A.

Schedule editor

2003 - 2007: several medias in Finland News reporter, editor and news reader

EDUCATION

September 2019 – present: online courses Several online courses to learn e.g. Python, PHP, WordPress, React, Scrum & Agile, SEO etc..

July - August 2019: Le Wagon Barcelona

Full Stack Ruby on Rails Bootcamp

9 weeks intensive coding bootcamp learning to use Ruby on Rails, HTML5, CSS / SCSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, SQL, MVC Architecture and GitHub.

1998 - 2003: University of Turku, Finland Master of Arts (literature, communications, languages)

LANGUAGE COMPETENCES

English Full working proficiency ★★★★ Native ★★★★★ Finnish French Working proficiency ★★★★ Working proficiency ★★★★ Spanish Limited working proficiency ★★★ German Swedish Limited proficiency ★★

INTERESTS

Coding and design, languages, hiking, gardening, reading